Lloyd E. Cotsen collection of Potter Family photographs,1865-1935: Finding Aid
Cotsen Children's Library
- Landscapes, 1880 May-1913 September; 1021 items
  - Lakefield moor, 1896 August 18; 334; 1 item 16.0 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ Lakefield Moor/ Aug 18 1896/ [ld]. Corners folded. Torn.
  - Esthwaite Water from Lakefield, 1896 August; 335; 1 item 11.0 x 15.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 1896/ [l d]/ Esthwaite.
  - Esthwaite Water, reeds, 1896 August; 336; 1 item 16.1 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 1896/ [l d]/ Esthwaite/ R Potter.
  - Stand of trees reflected in Esthwaite Water, 1896 August; 337; 1 item 16.0 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Esthwaite/ R Potter/ Aug 1896.
  - River Brathay, 1896 September 10; 338; 1 item 11.0 x 15.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 10 1896/ Brathay/ Loughrigg.
  - River Brathay, toward the Croft, 1896 September 10; 339; 1 item 11.0 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 10 1896/ R/ Brathay/ Windermere. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 340-343.
  - River Brathay, toward the Croft, 1896 September 10; 340; 1 item 11.0 x 15.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Croft/ Loughrigg/ Sep 10 1896/ R Potter. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 339, 341-343.
  - River Brathay, toward the Croft, 1896 September 10; 341; 1 item 11.0 x 15.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 10 1896. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 339-340, 342-343.
  - River Brathay, toward the Croft, 1896 September 10; 342; 1 item 11.1 x 15.3 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Croft/ Loughrigg/ Sep 10 1896/ R Potter. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 339-341, 343.
  - River Brathay, toward the Croft, 1896 September 10; 343; 1 item 11.1 x 15.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 10 1896. Inscribed in pencil by unknown hand: Brathay Croft Ambleside. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 339-342.
  - Esthwaite Water, 1896 September; 344; 1 item 7.1 x 9.8 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. Photographed during Lakefield stay. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 1896/ f16 1/8. Inscribed in pencil by unknown hand: Esthwaite.
  - Interior at Lakefield, 1896 September; 345; 1 item 7.3 x 9.8 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 1896.
  - Stand of trees by Esthwaite Water, 1896; 346; 1 item 16.4 x 21.3 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ 1896/ Esthwaite. Torn.
  - Lane bounded by houses up steep steps, 1897 April 19; 347; 1 item 12.0 x 16.4 cm.
    In catalog listed as possibly photographed in Sidmouth area. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Ap 19 1897/ NL HR. Inscribed in pencil, unknown hand: Ilfracombe?
  - Derwentwater from Lingholm, 1897 July 16; 348; 1 item 11.0 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ July 16 1897/ HK.
  - Derwentwater from Lingholm, 1897 July 25; 349; 1 item 10.9 x 15.6 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 25/ 1897/ W [+]d.
  - Derwentwater from Lingholm, 1897 July 26; 350; 1 item 7.0 x 9.8 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 26/ 1897/ W [+]d.
  - Skiddaw, seen across the Derwent or Derwentwater?, 1897 July 28; 351; 1 item 11.0 x 15.3 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 28 1897/ W [+]d.
  - Skiddaw, seen across the Derwent or Derwentwater?, 1897 July 28; 352; 1 item 10.9 x 15.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 28 1897/ W [T]d/ Skiddaw/ R Potter.
  - Derwentwater, 1897 July 28; 353; 1 item 15.9 x 21.3 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 28 1897/ W [+]d. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 354.
  - Derwentwater, 1897 July 28; 354; 1 item 15.8 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 28 1897/ W [+]d/ Derwent Water/ R Potter. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 353.
  - Fawe Park from the shore of Derwentwater, 1897 July 29; 355; 1 item 10.8 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 29 1897/ W d W/ Fawe Park/ NL/ R Potter. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 356.
  - Fawe Park from the shore of Derwentwater, 1897 July 29; 356; 1 item 11.0 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 29 1897/ NL/ Fawe Park/ W [+]d / R Potter. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 355.
  - Fawe Park from the shore of Derwentwater, 1897 July 29; 357; 1 item 10.8 x 15.2 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 29 1897/ NL W [+]d/ Fawe Park/ R Potter.
  - Fawe Park, from the shore of Derwentwater, 1897 July 29; 358; 1 item 10.9 x 15.6 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 29 1897/ NL W [+]d/ Derwent Water/ R Potter.
  - Derwentwater, 1897 July 29; 359; 1 item 15.9 x 21.3 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 1897/ W [+]d/ D.Water. Dated on basis of CTSN Potter 353.
  - Beached boats, Derwent Bay, 1897 August 10; 360; 1 item 16.5 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: 10 Aug 1897/ [s] l/ HK/ R.Potter/ Derwent Bay. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 361.
  - Beached boats, Derwent Bay, 1897 August 10; 361; 1 item 16.5 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ Aug 10 1897/ [l d]/ Derwent Bay. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 360.
  - Trees reflected along the shore of Derwent Bay, 1897 August 10; 362; 1 item 16.5 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 10 1897/ Derwent Bay.
  - Boat at dock, Derwent Bay, 1897 August 10; 363; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
  - Boats and boathouse, Derwent Bay, 1897 August 10; 364; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 10 1897/ [l d]. Inscribed in pencil, unknown hand: Derwent Bay. Corners folded.
  - Boathouse, Derwent Bay, 1897 August 10; 365; 1 item 16.5 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter / Aug 10 1897 / Derwent Bay. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 366.
  - Boathouse, Derwent Bay, 1897 August 10; 366; 1 item 16.5 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 10 1897/ [s.d w+]d. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 365.
  - Grounds of Lingholm?, 1897 August 13; 367; 1 item 10.9 x 15.2 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: 13 Aug 1897/ NL.
  - Cows in a field, 1897 August 17; 368; 1 item 10.9 x 15.6 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Precise location unknown. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 17 1897/ [s] l w d.
  - Derwentwater from a distance, 1897 August 18; 369; 1 item 11.0 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Precise location unknown. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 18 1897/ o [d] w d.
  - Bank of a river, 1897 August 19; 370; 1 item 10.7 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Precise location uknown. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 19 1897/ o d w d.
  - Two boats on the shore, Derwentwater?, 1897 August 23; 371; 1 item 11.1 x 15.4 cm.
    One boat named Mary, the other with fancy iron scrollwork. Photographed during Lingholm stay. Precise location unknown. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 23 1897/ NL/ [illegible]. Same location as CTSN Potter 376.
  - Two ponies in a field, with Skiddaw in the background, 1897 August 24; 372; 1 item 10.9 x 15.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Precise location unknown. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Skiddaw/ R Potter/ Aug 24 1897/ [illegible] w d.
  - Vale of Lorton, Scale Hill, 1897 August 27; 373; 1 item 12.0 x 16.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay.Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 27 1897/ [o l] w d. Inscribed in pencil, by Rupert Potter or unknown hand: Millbrook/ 1668/ Vale of Lorton/ Scale Hill.
  - Skiddaw, seen across Bassenthwaite Lake, 1897 August 27; 374; 1 item 15.9 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 27 1897/ [s] l w d/ Skiddaw/ 3054.
  - Interior of Crossthwaite Church, Keswick, 1897 August 28; 375; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ Crossthwaite Church/ Keswick/ Aug 28 1897/ [o l] w d.
  - Two boats on the shore, of Derwentwater?, 1897 August; 376; 1 item 11.1 x 15.4 cm.
    One boat named Mary, the other with fancy iron scrollwork. Photographed during Lingholm stay. Precise location unknown. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ Aug 1897. Same location as CTSN Potter 371.
  - Southey's monument, Crossthwaite Church, Keswick, 1897 September 3; 377; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ Southeys Monument/ Crossthwaite Church/ Sep 3 1897 o d w d.
  - Uprooted tree in the water, 1897 September 7; 378; 1 item 11.1 x 15.6 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. At Derwent Bay? Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 7 1897/ NL HK.
  - Derwent Bay boathouse, with Cat Bells reflected in the water, 1897 September 7; 379; 1 item 11.1 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 7 1897 HK. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 380.
  - Derwent Bay boathouse, with Cat Bells reflected in the water, 1897 September 7; 380; 1 item 11.1 x 15.6 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 7 1897 HK. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 379.
  - Skiddaw, Keswick, and Derwentwater, 1897 September 7; 381; 1 item 11.1 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 7 1897 HK. Inscribed in pencil, unknown hand: Derwentwater.
  - Beached boats under trees, Derwent Bay, 1897 September 8; 382; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 8 1897/ Sl wd /Derwent Bay.
  - Helvellyn across Thirlmere, from Armboth, 1897 September 15; 383; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ Sep 15 1897/ N3 wd/ Helvellyn across Thirlmere/ from Armboth.
  - Thirlmere, from Armboth, 1897 September 15; 384; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 15 1897/ N3 wd. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 385.
  - Thirlmere, from Armboth, 1897 September 15; 385; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ Armboth - Thirlmere/ Sep 15 1897/ N3 wd. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 384.
  - Three figures on a hillside, Skiddaw area, 1897 September 17; 386; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Two figures standing, one seated; standing figures possibly Beatrix and Canon Rawnsley? Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 17 1897/ N3 wd/ R Potter.
  - Skiddaw, 1897 September 17; 387; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 17 1897/ N3 wd/ R Potter. Corners folded.
  - Walla Crag seen from Lingholm, 1897 September 21; 388; 1 item 12.0 x 16.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 21 1897/ N3 wd [full op]/ Walla Crag (Derwent Water) from Lingholm.
  - Young trees by the water; at Fawe Park?, 1897 September 25; 389; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 25 1897/ N3 wd. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 390.
  - Young trees by the water; at Fawe Park?, 1897 September 25; 390; 1 item 16.4 x 12.1 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Fawe Park ?/ R Potter. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 389.
  - Skiddaw and Keswick, 1897 September 25; 391; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 25 1897/ N3 wd/ Skiddaw + Keswick.
  - Stone house among trees; possibly Rosetrees, on the grounds of Lingholm?, 1897 September 27; 392; 1 item 10.8 x 8.1 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 27 1897/ N3/ HK.
  - Sheep grazing by a stone wall, 1897 September 27; 393; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ Sep 27 1897/ N3.
  - Keswick from Cat Bells, 1897 September; 394; 1 item 12.0 x 16.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Potter/ Sep 1897/ Keswick from Catbells.
  - Skiddaw from Cat Bells, 1897 September; 395; 1 item 11.9 x 16.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Skiddaw from Catbells/ Sep 1897/ R Potter.
  - The Grange, Borrowdale, 1898 August 8; 396; 1 item 7.5 x 9.8 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Grange Borrowdale/ Aug 8 1898/ HK/ R Potter.
  - Fawe Park from the shore of Derwentwater, 1898 August 9; 397; 1 item 16.5 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 9 1898/ [l3] wd.
  - Newlands Valley, 1898 August 18; 398; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Newlands/ Aug 18 1898/ l3 wd.
  - Derwentwater, 1898 September 4; 399; 1 item 16.5 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 4 1898/ l3.
  - Woman sitting in the porch of a whitewashed house, 1898 September 6; 400; 1 item 16.5 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep. 6 1898/ l3. Corners folded. Torn.
  - Boats on the far bank of Derwent Bay, 1898 September 24; 401; 1 item 16.4 x 12.0 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Derwent Water/ R Potter/ Sep 24 1898/ l3.
  - Lingholm boat house, 1898; 402; 1 item 11.0 x 15.2 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Lingholm/ Boat House/ Derwent Water/ 1898/ R Potter.
  - Derwentwater, from Lingholm, 1899 July 29; 403; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Derwent Water/ Jy 29/ 1899/ l3.
  - Landscape near Grasmere, 1899 July; 404; 1 item 11.2 x 15.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 1899/ l3 wd. Inscribed in pencil, unknown hand: Lingholm?
  - Grasmere, 1899 July; 405; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 1899/ l3.
  - Grasmere, 1899 August 1; 406; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 1 1899/ l3/ R Potter.
  - Grasmere, 1899 August 2; 407; 1 item 12.0 x 16.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Grasmere/ Aug 2 1899/ l3 wd.
  - Unidentified house and boathouse, across Grasmere, 1899 August 9; 408; 1 item 12.0 x 16.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Grasmere/ l3 wd/ Aug 9/99.
  - Grasmere, from Grasmere Island?, 1899 August 9; 409; 1 item 12.0 x 16.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Two tiny figures in a boat at right. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 9 1899/ l3. Inscribed in pencil, unknown hand: Grasmere.
  - View of Grasmere from above, 1899 August 9; 410; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Four tiny figures in a boat, center. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 9 1899/ l3 [py]/ Grasmere.
  - Two boats on Grasmere, 1899 August 18; 411; 1 item 7.4 x 9.8 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 18 1899.
  - Dove Cottage, 1899 August 25; 412; 1 item 11.2 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Wordsworths Cottage/ Dove Cottage/ 1803 Grasmere/ Aug 25 1899/ ol B/ R Potter// Dove Cottage/ front view.
  - View of Grasmere, 1899 August; 413; 1 item 11.2 x 15.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 1899/ S3.
  - Town of Grasmere from Kelbarrow Garden, 1899 August; 414; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Grasmere/ from Kelbarrow Garden/ R Potter/ Aug 1899/ l3 wd.
  - Moored boats and stone wall along shore of Grasmere, 1899 August; 415; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 1899/ l3 wd/ Grasmere.
  - River Brathay, 1899 September 1; 416; 1 item 11.0 x 15.1 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Brathay/ Sep 1 1899/ R Potter.
  - River Brathay, 1899 September; 417; 1 item 11.2 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: R Brathay/ Sep 1899/ R Potter. Possibly 1 Sep 1899.
  - 'Rash Judgments'; Rydal Lake, 1899 September 8; 418; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Rash Judgments/ Sep 8 1899/ R Potter/ Rydal Lake/ from N West. Title is a quotation from Wordsworth. Either from Tintern Abbey: Neither evil tongues, rash judgments, nor the sneers of selfish men, nor greetings where no kindness is, nor all the dreary intercourse of daily life, shall ever prevail against us. Or taken from Poems on the Naming of Places: IV, first line: A narrow girdle of rough stones and crags... ending: and POINT RASH-JUDGMENT is the name it bears. However, the latter poem refers to a location on Grasmere.
  - Broadram road, 1899 September 8; 419; 1 item 10.8 x 15.3 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: 8/ Sep 8 1899/ Broadram/ R Potter// Broadram Road/ to Dunmaile Raise/ showing garden/ across the Road/ where death of some/ one mentioned in/ Wordsworths poem/ occurred.
  - Roucky outcropping, Grasmere area, 1899 September 8; 420; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 8 99/ l3 R Potter.
  - Helvellyn, 1899 September 13; 421; 1 item 16.4 x 21.3 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 13 1899/ l3 wd/ Helvellyn/ R Potter.
  - Rydal Water, 1899; 422; 1 item 11.4 x 15.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Rydal / 1899 / R Potter.
  - Launrigg, 1899 September; 423; 1 item 11.0 x 15.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Launrigg/ Sep 1899/ R Potter.
  - Kelbarrow, 1899; 424; 1 item 16.3 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lingholm stay. Title supplied from inscription. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Kelbarrow/ Sep 1899/ R Potter.
  - View of grounds, Lakefield, 1900 July; 425; 1 item 16.3 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 1900/ R Potter/ l3.
  - Esthwaite water, haystacks, seen from the grounds of Lakefield, 1900 July; 426; 1 item 16.4 x 21.4 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 1900/ l 3 S.
  - Esthwaite water, seen from the grounds of Lakefield, 1900 July; 427; 1 item 11.1 x 15.2 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: July 1900/ S3/ Esthwaite.
  - Esthwaite water, 1900 August 8; 428; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 8 1900/ l3. Inscribed in pencil, unknown hand: Esthwaite. Corners folded.
  - Shore of Esthwaite water?, 1900 August 8; 429; 1 item 16.5 x 21.7 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 8 1900/ l3.
  - Lakefield house seen across Esthwaite water, 1900 August 8; 430; 1 item 16.5 x 216 cm.
  - Stand of trees reflected in Esthwaite water, 1900 August 16; 431; 1 item 12.0 x 15.3 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Aug 16 1900/ l3.
  - Trees and reeds, Esthwaite water, 1900 August 16; 432; 1 item 16.2 x 21.5 cm.
  - Trees and reeds, Esthwaite water, 1900 August 16; 433; 1 item 16.4 x 21.5 cm.
  - Garden pavilion and grounds, Lakefield, 1900 August 20; 434; 1 item 12.0 x 16.3 cm.
    Photographed during Lakefield stay. Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Eeswyke/ R Potter/ Aug 20 1900/ S3. Inscribed in ballpoint, unknown hand: (Lakefield).